CURRICULUM VITAE

I am a driven and motivated young professional with a variety of skills ranging from leadership and motivation of my staff, organization, and language expertise to eagerness to learn new skills and grow in the field of Software Development. However, my true passion since secondary school and my studies at the University of Glasgow has always been Computing Science and Software Engineering. This is the reason why I have dedicated myself to pursuing my dream of working as a Software Developer professionally and as a full-blown career. To build upon this passion, I have recently graduated from a coding Traineeship as a full stack developer including completing 2 real-world projects successfully to specification using a wide range of programming languages. I have excellent customer service, communication, teamwork and organisation skills and a strong work ethic. I am looking forward to establishing a career in the development field where I can prove myself as an asset.

PERSONAL DETAILS

NAME: Lukas Michalek

RESIDES: Winsford

TRANSPORT: Full UK driving license

LANGUAGES: English, Slovak, Polish, German

RIGHT TO WORK: Pre-settled status

CONTACT DETAILS: (M) 07442 096838

(E) <u>luke.michalek@gmail.com</u>
(W) <u>https://lukasmichalek.co.uk/</u>

(GH) https://github.com/lukas-michalek (please email to request access)

(LI) https://www.linkedin.com/in/lukasmichalek/

CODING TRAINEESHIP IT Career Switch Ltd

Coding Traineeship - Full stack developer

1-year program

During the traineeship I had to demonstrate a very competent level of the following programming languages and technical skills

- HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript
 PHP, SQL, React, jQuery
 Python, Node.js, Bootstrap
- Command line Git, Github
- Remote API access

ADDITIONAL TECHNOLOGIES:

PostgreSQL, Java

DEVELOPMENT EXPERIENCE:

Below are the two briefs of development projects I completed with IT Career Switch which can be found in my bio: https://lukasmichalek.co.uk/

Portfolio Project #1: "Gazetteer"

The specification was to reply to a website specification for a map-based app to provide information on countries, with a focus on a "mobile-first" development. Preferably using a framework, to then develop HTML, CSS and

JavaScript with JQuery modules that use PHP server-based components to source data from third-party APIs (Geonames, OpenWeather). The solution is assessed on its delivery to specification, functionality, and usability.

Portfolio Project #2: "Company Directory"

A more rigorous reply to this specification was required as a user requirements document was needed to be prepared which, when signed off, triggers the release of SQL allowing to develop a "mobile-first" application to maintain a company personnel database (MySQL). Sign off is only achieved upon the student supplying an independently witnessed document providing confirmation of the system's ability to perform error-free.

CAREER HISTORY:

Jan 2024 – Present POSITION HELD:

Wincanton plc Team Leader (Loading Processes)

- Problem-solving
- Delegated tasks
- Led by example
- Coached to improve team member skill sets
- Organised work
- Communicated goals

May 2022 – May 2023 POSITION HELD:

Language Empire Itd Language Interpreter

- Provided interpretation services from English to Slovak and Czech language to clients in various settings, such as legal proceedings, medical appointments, business meetings, conferences
- Communicated with clients through face-to-face conversations, video calls, or over the phone

Oct 2020 – Sep 2021 POSITION HELD:

TAHAG, Switzerland Food Production Operative

- Daily communication in German
- Supported and aided colleagues
- Teamwork

May 2020 – Oct 2020 POSITION HELD:

Tesco, Slovakia Transportation Clerk

- Received, inspected, and verified incoming shipments
- Ensured all shipping documents were properly prepared and in compliance with all regulations
- Followed safety protocols and procedures when handling freight
- Worked collaboratively with other departments to ensure smooth order processing

Jun 2018 – Mar 2020 POSITION HELD:

ENCO s.r.o, Germany Operational Manager

- Managed more than 70 employees of a foundry and fettling shop in MAN Energy Solutions, Augsburg, Germany
- Communicated with colleagues and authorities in German

- Administration, material planning and ordering, employee evaluation, stock control
- Dealt with stressful situations constructively, effectively, and in a calm matter
- Helped employees with daily problems related to life in Germany (doctor, dentist, bank, correspondence)

Jul 2016 – Mar 2017 POSITION HELD:

Tailored Recruitment Services Ltd Warehouse Operative

- Efficiently picked up customer orders (clothes)
- Located products using technology
- Retrieved orders according to quantity and size, ensuring accuracy
- Adhered to health and safety policies and quality standards

Jan 2016 – Jul 2016 POSITION HELD:

SAVY Courses, Slovakia English Language Teacher

- Taught different groups with different levels of English such as Elementary, Lower Intermediate, Intermediate, and Upper-Intermediate
- Communication skills, ability to work under pressure, and organisational skills were greatly improved
- Upgraded listening skills and learned how to be patient with customers

Jun 2015 – Jan 2016 POSITION HELD:

AdamsFood Zone Controller

- Ensuring effective line-running
- Fully trained in OLYMPUS, ILAPAK and ALPMA systems
- Trained in Control of Substances Hazardous to Health (COSHH)

May 2014 – Jun 2015 POSITION HELD:

Driving Edge Warehouse Operative

- Acquired the correct load restraint techniques
- Improved accuracy, ability to work under pressure, and attention to detail
- Developed a great sense of teamwork with colleagues
- Enhanced sense of responsibility and reliability

Oct 2012 – Aug 2013 POSITION HELD:

Repack Ltd Warehouse Operative

- Made sure that the final product was not in any way harmful or defective, and also ensured that existing products met a set quality standards
- Met deadlines on time, and encouraged and oversaw co-workers

Jun 2012 – Oct 2012 POSITION HELD:

Sport Hotel Alexandria, Slovakia Hotel Receptionist

- Through diplomacy, honesty, and utmost respect, interacted with quests and colleagues and greatly improved customer service skills as a result
- Developed a high level of organisational and time management skills
- Computer skills included the ability to spreadsheet and word processing programs at a highly proficient level

Supported the Executive Director and other staff members

May 2010 – Jul 2011 POSITION HELD:

24-7 Recruitment Services Warehouse Operative

- Unloaded trailers using various equipment (pump truck, PPT)
- Continuously improved performance
- Worked as part of a team, supporting colleagues at all times to meet deadlines and targets
- Developed flexibility and the ability to deal with problems in a calm and professional manner
- Improved accuracy concerning all paperwork, paying particular attention to detail

Certifications and Licenses:

2022 – Present Cleverlance Enterprise Solutions s.r.o, Czech Republic

Software Tester Certificate

2016 – Present Driver Certificate of Professional Competence

2015 – Present Selby College

Business and Administration Certificate

2013 – Present Lakeshire College

Level 2 Customer Service Certificate

2011 – Present University of Liverpool

IELTS Certificate 7.0

Cambridge ESOL Level 3 Certificate in English

EDUCATION:

2023 - 2024 IT Career Switch Ltd

Coding Traineeship - Full stack developer

2022 – 2023 Codecademy

Full Stack Software Engineer Path in Computer Programming

2006 – 2010 Secondary Technical School, Slovakia

A Levels from Electrical Engineering